RAVI DEEPAK TRIVEDI

Freelance Web Developer, 3rd Year Computer Science Student

@ ravi28trivedi@gmail.com

519-965-1642

♀ Canada

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ravitrivedi07/

nttps://github.com/R-bjorn

SUMMERY

Honoured by Dean and Lead by Experts specializing in Web Development. Experienced with all stages of development cycle for dynamic web projects. Wellversed in JavaScript, React, Html/css, php, WordPress, Bootstrap and GitHub. Strong background in management and leadership.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Object Oriented Languages: Python, Java, C++/C#
- Web Development (Front-end / Back-end): HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React, Perl
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux
- Software Tools: IntelliJ, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Android Studio, Rider, Reactide, Adobe Illustrator

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science - 3.7 GPA

University of Windsor

🛗 Sept 2019 - Present

Ontario, Canada

• Specialization: Game Development

Minor: Physics - Astronomy

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer Intern

Novavet Pharma

May 2021 - August 2021

Q Ahmadabad, Gujarat - Remote

- Collaborated with UI and UX personnel to develop friendly and interactive websites that ensures high customer traffic, page views and user experience which resulted in a 42% increase in sales revenue.
- Designed company logo using Adobe Illustrator to strengthen company brand and identity.
- Implemented a server that expedited document generation and searches functionality by 20%.
- Developed, coded, installed, tested, debugged and documented web applications using HTML5, CSS, React and JavaScript on Visual Studio Code.

Front-end Developer Intern

Crew's Closet

🛗 June 2020 - October 2020

? Toronto, Ontario - Remote

- Created ecommerce websites on Shopify with a team of clients of a start up company
 which met requirements for objectives to reach maximum customers, increase sales
 and profitability of the business.
- Analyzed known design shortcomings using wire-framing, diagramming and mapping to help team members visualize existing product limitations and evaluate proposed solutions.
- Researched and developed new technology designs and Integrated several different APIs such as CashFree and Shyplite to framework.

PROJECTS

Web Design Projects

Calculator

- Implemented basic math operators with JavaScript and Designed a responsive layout for calculator.
- Created a function to populate the display when user click the number buttons and added keyboard support.

Filter Fun

- Designed a website with a sole purpose to changes the appearance of an image.
- Added multiple options for user to choose with an interactive website.

Paint

 Developed a responsive design for user to paint on the website with different colored pens and brushes.

To Do List

- Designed an interactive website for organizing tasks and reminders for everyday use.
- Outperformed by adding a push notification functionality for User Experience.

Software Projects

Store Inventory System

- Executed an inventory management system whose main functionality apart from calculating the inventory include predicting the requirement for the next demand.
- Outlined a function using Java to keep track of the shelf life of resources.

Flight Tracking System

- Developed a viable software system to obtain and process flight data in real-time on the ground while the flight is still in progress.
- Integrated a functionality to control airspace on the route and to collect specific details about the planned routing, altitude, and speed of the plane.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Dean's Honour List (2020 2021)
- Most valued player at Gujarat State Football Association (GSFA) under 16 age group.
- Founded Science Innovation Club in highschool (Krishna - School of Science) with classmates to encourage innovative ideas and projects.